Guide to the Ithaca Garden Club records, 1943-2009.
Ithaca Garden Club records
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Ithaca Garden Club records, 1943-2009.
6881
Ithaca Garden Club.
Correspondence, Manuscripts, Newspapers, Printed Materials, Scrapbooks
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Yearbooks, scrapbooks, albums containing clippings and programs from events, executive board files, and civic development project folders from the Ithaca Garden Club.
ORGANIZATIONAL HISTORY
Founded in 1922, the Ithaca Garden Club is a longstanding member of the City Federation of Women's Organizations (CFWO) in Ithaca, NY.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Yearbooks, scrapbooks, albums containing clippings and programs from events, executive board files, and civic development project folders from the Ithaca Garden Club.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Ithaca Garden Club.
Subjects:
Gardening.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
CONTAINER LIST
- Bylaws and Constitution, 1948-1975 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Obituary - Mrs. Livingston Farrand (Daisy), 1952-1989 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Annual Report, 1950-1964 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Miscellaneous Flower Show Brochures (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Handbook for Flower Shows, 1997 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- The Ithaca Garden Club Yearbooks, 1950-2009 (Box 1, Folder 6-10)
- Report on The House and Garden Tour, June 17, 1960 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Informal Flower Show "Spring-Singing and Winging", Apr. 19, 1961 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Reports - Reta B. Dixon, 1960 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Holiday House, Dec. 21, 1960 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- The Garden Club of Ithaca, N.Y.: The Women's Community Building, 1960 (Box 1, Folder 15)
- House and Garden Tour and Flower Show of the Garden Club of Ithaca, May 11-12, 1956 (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Holiday House, Dec. 16, 1959 (Box 1, Folder 17)
- "Color-ama" Autumn Drama, Sep. 20, 1958 (Box 1, Folder 18)
- Garden Club Minutes, 1967-1969 (Box 1, Folder 19)
- Ithaca Garden Club, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 20)
- Flower Show Photographs, May, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 21)
- The Garden Club of Ithaca Christmas Show, 1966 (Box 1, Folder 22)
- Standard Christmas Flower Show, Dec. 7, 1966 (Box 1, Folder 23)
- Seasonal Standard Flower Show, May 21, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 24)
- Home and Garden Tour and Flower Show, Sep. 16, 1964 (Box 1, Folder 25)
- "Noel-Noel" Report of Horticulture Chairman, Dec. 7, 1966 (Box 1, Folder 26)
- "Noel-Noel" Extra Information on Show not recorded in Chairman Report Book, Dec. 7, 1966 (Box 1, Folder 27)
- "Noel-Noel" Report of Chairman of Judges, Dec. 7, 1966 (Box 1, Folder 28)
- Clippings from Papers, 1964 (Box 1, Folder 29)
- Girl Scouts of the United States of America (Box 1, Folder 30)
- The Alfaretta May Hale Junior Award of Ten Dollars, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 31)
- Ithaca Garden Club, 1964 (Box 1, Folder 32)
- The Garden Club of Ithaca Scrapbooks Vol. 2-4, 1951-1966 (Box 2)
- The Garden Club of Ithaca Scrapbooks Vol. 5-10, 1966-1985 (Box 3)
- De Witt Park, 1969-1970 (Box 4, Folder 1)
- Civic Beautification, 1971-1972 (Box 4, Folder 2)
- Ithaca Garden Club Meeting Minutes, 1969-1971 (Box 4, Folder 3)
- Purple Ribbon Award Application, 1969 (Box 4, Folder 4)
- New York State Bronze Medal for Juniors (Girl Scouts) Application, 1974 (Box 4, Folder 5)
- Blue and White Rosette Application, 1974 (Box 4, Folder 6)
- Blue Rosette Award, 1971 (Box 4, Folder 7)
- "Open Doors" Flower Show, 1971 (Box 4, Folder 8)
- Procedure Files, 1971-1975 (Box 4, Folder 10)
- Strolling Standard Flower Show, 1974 (Box 4, Folder 11)
- 50th Anniversary, 1971 (Box 4, Folder 12)
- Committee Reports, 1979-1981 (Box 4, Folder 13)
- Parlimentary and Miscellaneous Documents, 1979-1981 (Box 4, Folder 14)
- Civic Development, 1983-1984 (Box 4, Folder 15)
- Standard Flower Show, 1984 (Box 4, Folder 16)
- Hangwer Theater, 1980 (Box 4, Folder 17)
- Treasurer's Reports, 1981 (Box 4, Folder 18)
- "Come Fly With Me" Flower Show, Oct. 15, 1980 (Box 4, Folder 19)
- Ithaca Garden Club, Inc., 1979-1981 (Box 4, Folder 20)
- Burling Woods Dedication Ceremony, June 13, 1979 (Box 4, Folder 21)
- Burling Woods, 1979-1990 (Box 4, Folder 22)
- President's Report and Misc. Documents, 1976-1977 (Box 4, Folder 23)
- National Council Award #10-B Brewer Certificate, 1976 (Box 4, Folder 24)
- Report of "We, the people" - A Home and Garden Show, 1976 (Box 4, Folder 25)
- "We, the people" - A Home and Garden Show, 1969-1970 (Box 4, Folder 26)
- Committee Reports, 1975-1977 (Box 4, Folder 27)
- Crab Memorial Tree Project, 1973-1974 (Box 4, Folder 28)
- Civic Development, 1973-1978 (Box 4, Folder 29)
- Unsolicited Citation New York State Award #13, 1976 (Box 5, Folder 1)
- Mrs. John Nagle, President Ithaca Garden Club, Apr.1971 - Mar.1973 (Box 5, Folder 2)
- Ithaca Garden Club, Mrs. H.B.Rumph, Jr., 1976 (Box 5, Folder 3)
- Tompkins Hospital Landscaping: Photos and Plans, 1980-1983 (Box 5, Folder 4)
- Ithaca Garden Club, Inc., 1981-1983 (Box 5, Folder 5)
- IGC Minutes, Budget, and Other Documents, 1985 (Box 5, Folder 6)
- Ithaca Garden Club Correspondence, 1983-1985 (Box 5, Folder 7)
- Garden Club Minutes, May 1982 - Jan. 1985 (Box 5, Folder 8-9)
- History of Project Reconstruction Home, 1988-1990 (Box 5, Folder 10)
- Yearbook "Our Trees, Our Treasure", 1990-1991 (Box 5, Folder 11)
- Various Garden Club Documents, Feb. 1991 - Mar. 1993 (Box 5, Folder 12)
- Unsolicited Award Application, Oct. 4, 1989 (Box 5, Folder 13)
- Elsie M. Cook Award for Landscaping, 1988-1990 (Box 5, Folder 14)
- Ithaca Garden Club Documents, 1989-1991 (Box 5, Folder 15)
- Civic Development, 1988-1991 (Box 5, Folder 16)
- Garden Study Award, Oct. 26,1988 (Box 5, Folder 17)
- Civic Development Award: Marcham Garden, 1989 (Box 5, Folder 18)
- Certificate of Merit for Blue Star Memorial By-Ways, 1983 (Box 5, Folder 19)
- Collection of Ithaca Garden Club Photographs, 1986-1988 (Box 5, Folder 20)
- Crabapple Replacement Project Civic Development, 1987 (Box 5, Folder 21)
- Civic Development, 1985-1987 (Box 5, Folder 22)
- Corporate Meetings, 1992-1995 (Box 5, Folder 23)
- Executive Board Minutes of the Ithaca Garden Club, Mar. 5, 1985 - Mar. 1987 (Box 6, Folder 1)
- Executive Board, 1989-1991 (Box 6, Folder 2)
- Sixth District Tompkins County Chairman, 1987-1992 (Box 6, Folder 3)
- Ithaca Garden Club Documents, 1987-1989 (Box 6, Folder 4)
- Executive Board Minutes of the Ithaca Garden Club, Mar. 1987 - Mar. 1989 (Box 6, Folder 5)
- Executive Board, 1991-1992 (Box 6, Folder 6)
- Tea at Elsner's, 1992 (Box 6, Folder 7)
- Junior Gardening: Susan McCutcheon and Donna Munger, 1991-1993 (Box 6, Folder 8)
- House and Garden Tour, June 10, 1992 (Box 6, Folder 9)
- Ithaca Garden Club Scrapbook, 1989-1990 (Box 6, Folder 10)
- Board Meeting Minutes, 1993-1994 (Box 6, Folder 11)
- Citation for a Flower Show in a Public Building, 1994 (Box 6, Folder 12)
- "A Country Garden" Garden Tour and Tea, June, 1996 (Box 6, Folder 13)
- Executive Board Documents, 1993-1995 (Box 6, Folder 14)
- "Summer Pleasures" Garden Tour Boutique and Stawberry Social, June 26, 2002 (Box 6, Folder 15)
- Christmas Tea, 1994 (Box 6, Folder 16)
- The Lillian Arend Horticulturist of the Year, 1994 (Box 6, Folder 17)
- Garden Club Questionnaire, Mar. 1995 (Box 6, Folder 18)
- Miscellaneous Documents (Box 6, Folder 19)
- Ithaca Garden Club District 06 (Box 6, Folder 20)
- State, Regional, and National Information of Federated Garden Clubs, 1993-1995 (Box 6, Folder 21)
- IGC Board Minutes, May 1995 - Mar. 1997 (Box 6, Folder 22)
- Ithaca Garden Club Scrapbook, 1992-1995 (Box 6, Folder 23-24)
- Miscellaneous Documents (Box 6, Folder 25-26)
- President Judy Barker, 1997-1999 (Box 7, Folder 1-2)
- "Celebrating an American Generation" Flower Show, Sep. 19, 2001 (Box 7, Folder 3)
- "Earth, Wind, and Fire" Flower Show, Sep. 24, 1997 (Box 7, Folder 4)
- "Captivating Color" Flower Show, Sep. 29, 1999 (Box 7, Folder 5)
- Committee Reports, 1997-1999 (Box 7, Folder 6)
- Kitchen Tour, 1997 (Box 7, Folder 7)
- Christmas Tea at the Zelko's, DEc. 11, 1996 (Box 7, Folder 8)
- Standard Flower Show Citation Award Application, Sep. 30, 1999 (Box 7, Folder 9)
- Standard Flower Show Citation Award Application, Sep. 30, 2001 (Box 7, Folder 10)
- Annual Spring Luncheon, 2002-2003 (Box 7, Folder 11)
- New Member Tea, Oct. 2002 (Box 7, Folder 12)
- Committee Reports, 2001-2003 (Box 7, Folder 13)
- Board Meeting Minutes, July 2001 - May 2003 (Box 7, Folder 14)
- "Celebrating an Admirable Generation" Flower Show, Sep. 19, 2001 (Box 7, Folder 15)
- Awards, 2001-2003 (Box 7, Folder 16)
- Johnson Art Museum: Art and Flowers Exhibit, May 21, 2003 (Box 7, Folder 17)
- Bus Tours, June 2002 - June 2003 (Box 7, Folder 18)
- President's Book: Mary Lou Garrity, 2001-2003 (Box 7, Folder 19-20)
- President Jeanne Yarussi, 1999-2001 (Box 7, Folder 21-22)
- Women's Community Building (Box 7, Folder 23)
- City Federation (Box 7, Folder 24)
- Civic Development, 1999-2000 (Box 7, Folder 25)
- Blue Star Dedication and History, Sep. 12, 2000 (Box 7, Folder 26)
- President Donna Clark's Resource Book, 2003-2005 (Box 8, Folder 1-2)
- President Resources, 2005-2007 (Box 8, Folder 3-4)
- Ithaca Garden Club Scrapbooks, 1995-2003 (Box 9)